

Status: Junior Data Scientist at Exegetic **Fields**: Data Science, Consulting **Techs**: R, Shiny, Bash, Git, SQL, Python

Activities: Mountain biking, Trail running, Coffee snob

Stellenbosch, South Africa http://marinuslouw.github.io/ marinuslouw@icloud.com +27 83 385 2564

Summary

Economics graduate with data science experience in a consulting environment. Currently working as a Junior data scientist at Exegetic Analytics. Master studies focused on micro- and macro-economics and a solid foundation in econometrics and financial econometrics.

Experience

Junior Data Scientist - Exegetic Analytics

Dec 2018 - present

- $\cdot \ \, \text{Accumulate further experience with programming languages such as R and Python}.$
- · Solve complex problems and consult for a range of companies in various industries.

Part-time Data Analyst - Du Toitskloof Wines

Apr 2018 - Dec 2018

· On a part-time basis, investigate and improve current pricing strategies with the use of econometrics.

Formal Education

Graduated as MComm Economics - University of Stellenbosch

2016 - 2017

- · Focus Areas: Quantitative Finance, Financial Econometrics, Time-Series Econometrics, Macroeconomics
- · Dissertation topic: "Measuring company innovation using CEO and board member age: a quantitative and empirical approach"

Graduated as BCommHons Economics - University of Stellenbosch

2015 - 2016

· Dissertation topic: "The underlying risks in the Local Government Debt of China"

Graduated as BComm Economics - University of Stellenbosch

2012 - 2014

· Economics Major

Supplementary Education

Completed course: Financial Econometrics - University of Stellenbosch

2nd Semester 2018

· Masters course in Financial Econometrics, by Nico Katzke - Head Quantitative Analyst of Prescient Securities.

http://marinuslouw.github.io/ · github.com/marinuslouw